<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Jamie Magee</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Jamie Magee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>

	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


    <item>
      <title>Twitter Hashflags (_Hash-what?_)</title>
      <link>/blog/twitter-hashflags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/blog/twitter-hashflags/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tweeted out a hastag, and discovered a small image attached to the side of it? It could be for #StPatricksDay, #MarchForOurLives, or whatever #白白白白白白白白白白 is meant to be. These are hashflags.
A hashflag, sometimes called Twitter emoji, is a small image that appears after a #hashtag for special events. They are not regular emoji, and you can only use them on the Twitter website, or the official Twitter apps.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>A survey of robots.txt - part two</title>
      <link>/blog/a-survey-of-robots-txt-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/blog/a-survey-of-robots-txt-part-two/</guid>
      <description>In part one of this article, I collected robots.txt from the top 1 million sites on the web. In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to do some analysis, and see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything interesting to find from all the files I&amp;rsquo;ve collected.
First we&amp;rsquo;ll start with some setup.
%matplotlib inline import pandas as pd import numpy as np import glob import os import matplotlib  Next I&amp;rsquo;m going to load the content of each file into my pandas dataframe, calculate the file size, and store that for later.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>A survey of robots.txt - part one</title>
      <link>/blog/a-survey-of-robots-txt-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/blog/a-survey-of-robots-txt-part-one/</guid>
      <description>After reading CollinMorris&amp;rsquo;s analysis of favicons of the top 1 million sites on the web, I thought it would be interesting to do the same for other common parts of websites that often get overlooked.
The robots.txt file is a plain text file found at on most websites which communicates information to web crawlers and spiders about how to scan a website.. For example, here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from robots.txt for google.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Setting up nginx reverse proxy with Let&#39;s Encrypt on unRAID</title>
      <link>/blog/setting-up-nginx-reverse-proxy-with-lets-encrypt-on-unraid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/blog/setting-up-nginx-reverse-proxy-with-lets-encrypt-on-unraid/</guid>
      <description>Late last year I set about building a new NAS to replace my aging HP ProLiant MicroServer N36L (though that&amp;rsquo;s a story for a different post). I decided to go with unRAID as my OS, over FreeNAS that I&amp;rsquo;d been running previously, mostly due to the simpler configuration, ease of expanding an array, and support for Docker and KVM.
Docker support makes it a lot easier to run some of the web apps that I rely on like Plex, Sonarr, CouchPotato and more, but accessing them securely outside my network is a different story.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Do you really want &#34;bank grade&#34; security in your SSL? Danish edition</title>
      <link>/blog/do-you-want-bank-grade-ssl-danish-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/blog/do-you-want-bank-grade-ssl-danish-edition/</guid>
      <description>I recently saw an article on /r/programming called Do you really want &amp;ldquo;bank grade&amp;rdquo; security in your SSL? Here&amp;rsquo;s how Aussie banks fare. The author used the Qualys SSL Labs test to determine how good Aussie banks&amp;rsquo; SSL implementations really are. I thought the article was great, and gave good, actionable feedback. At the time of writing this two of the banks listed have already improved their SSL scores.
It got me thinking: how well (or badly) do banks in Denmark fare?</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Continuously deploy Jekyll to Azure Web Apps</title>
      <link>/blog/continuous-deployment-jekyll-to-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/blog/continuous-deployment-jekyll-to-azure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about writing a blog for a while now, but there are just so many blogging platforms out there to choose from. I finally settled on Jekyll as it&amp;rsquo;s really lightweight (compared to platforms like Wordpress), it has an active development community, and you can write all your articles in Markdown.
Many Jekyll users host their Jekyll sites through GitHub Pages, and there are a lot of advantages to this:</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>